# **Milad Amirian**

5947 Helmcrest Drive, Riverside, CA 92509 • (714) 390-7797 • amiriania@gmail.com

## **SUMMARY**

Experienced Sales Account Manager with an aerospace engineering degree and demonstrated history of working with major accounts in the aerospace and technology industries. Passionate about technology and security with self-taught coding experience in HTML, CSS and JavaScript (including frameworks such as Vue.JS, Bootstrap 4 & React).

# **EXPERIENCE**

## COLLINS AEROSPACE

Regional Sales Account Manager 2012 - Present (Anaheim, CA)

- Increased spares components sales by 27% from 2012 through 2016 despite reducing legacy install-base which directly led to promotion and relocation to the Anaheim facility.
- Achieved over 91% win-rate of all campaigns (\$137m) from 2016 to 2020 within assigned accounts (U.S role) which directly led to being assigned additional major accounts in the Middle East region.
- Managed complex business relationships with key clients including Emirates, Cathay Pacific, British Airways and Singapore Airlines
- Presented pricing strategies to senior management, generating \$3m in additional annual revenue.
- Created clear strategies on retrofits to increase opportunities for up-selling services, kits and increasing client's inventory to grow overall sales, which resulted in \$6m of additional kit sales.
- Influenced priorities of Customer Services, Engineering, Supply Chain, Operations, Manufacturing and Shipping departments to ensure business-objective success.
- Created a standardized metrics deck for senior management's weekly 'pulse' reviews with specific metrics on delivery rate, revenue run-rate, on-time performance, customer feedback and upcoming business milestones.
- Standardized customer visit across the business with focus on performance metrics and alleviating client pressure points, which resulted in more efficient and constructive customer visits and directly enhanced client rapport.
- Monitored Accounts Receivable on weekly basis for customer balances and acted as primary interface between customer and the company to facilitate any pending payment issues.

### **SWIFT AEROSPACE**

Account Manager
2010 - 2011 (London, G.B)

- Management of twelve mid-size accounts in a fast-paced and target driven environment.
- Daily engagement with customers to understand critical & technical requirements and then sourcing the custom products on the open market based on pricing, availability and quickest delivery to meet the customer's exact requirements.

- Applied individual profit margins to each sale to meet customer requirements and alignment to Swift's profit targets.
- Ensured all products were sourced and supplied with the correct certifications and manufacturing traceability.
- Maintained and developed strong relationships with customers through exceptional customer service and regular on-site presence.

# APPLE INC.

Mac Specialist & Trainer 2004 - 2007 (London, G.B)

- Troubleshooted customer computers and performed hardware (RAM, Bluetooth modules, HD expansions) and software upgrades.
- Performed live presentations of all Apple's software products in front of up to 300 visitors at a time.
- Provided training to customers seeking more advanced skills in audio and video production editing.
- Gained certifications for all of Apple's applications designed for professional audio & video production (Logic Pro, Motion & Final Cut Pro.
- Implemented excellent customer service while assisting customers with technical support issues, repairs and system upgrades.

# **EDUCATION**

 ${\it Master of Business Administration}$  - California State Fullerton - Irvine

2018 - Present (Irvine, CA)

Aerospace Systems Engineering (Hons) - University of Hertfordshire

2006 - 2010 (Hatfield, G.B)

Audio Engineering Diploma - School of Audio Engineering (SAE Institute) 2001 - 2003 (London, G.B)

# ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

### • **CERTIFICATIONS:**

Frontend Developer (Udemy & FreeCodeCamp), MS Excel level 3, Finance for non-financial Managers, Contract Creation and Negotiation.

# • COMPUTER SKILLS:

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap4, MS Office, Outlook, Windows & MAC OS, Final Cut Pro, Motion, Logic X, Catia V5, Team Center, JD Edwards (MRP), Oracle CRM, Adobe Creative Suite.

#### • COMPETENCIES:

Complex technical sales cycles, contract negotiation, solution selling, P&L management, exceptional interpersonal skills and relationship management.